Guide to the James Lees-Milne Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1923-97; Series I; 7.35; (18 boxes)
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - Loewenstein, Josephine; Loewenstein, Rupert, 1984-97, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 478)
    - Longford, Elizabeth Harman Packenham, Countess of, 1931, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 479)
    - Longman, Elizabeth, 1991-97, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 480)
    - Lowe, Ian; Lowe, Mary, 1978-95 (Box 10, Folder 481)
    - Lowenthal, David, 1990 Jan 22 (Box 10, Folder 482)
    - Lowndes, Belloc (Marie Belloc- Lowndes), 1935-43 (Box 10, Folder 483)
    - Lownie, Andrew, 1993 Sep 23 (Box 10, Folder 484)
    - Lubbock, Percy, 1956 Jan 26 (Box 10, Folder 485)
    - Lukacs, John, 1981-97 (Box 10, Folder 486)
    - Lutyens, Mary; Links, J. G., 1975-97 (Box 10, Folder 487)
    - Lycett, Andrew, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 488)
    - Lycett-Green, Candida, 1986-97 (Box 10, Folder 489)
    - Lygon, Coote, 1987-93 (Box 10, Folder 490)
    - "M" general, 1927-97 (Box 10, Folder 491)
    - Macaulay, Rose, 1943-49, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 492)
    - Maccarrone, Michele, 1968-70 (Box 10, Folder 493)
    - McCarthy, Fiona, 1996-97 (Box 10, Folder 494)
    - McCorquodale, Charles, 1988 Feb 9 (Box 11, Folder 495)
    - McDouall, Robin, 1980-83 (Box 11, Folder 496)
    - McGarvie, Michael, 1988 Feb 5 (Box 11, Folder 497)
    - Machin, David, 1994-96 (Box 11, Folder 498)
    - Mackenzie, Compton, Sir, 1951 Jul 22 (Box 11, Folder 499)
    - McLeod, Kirsty, 1990-91 (Box 11, Folder 500)
    - MacLeish, Archibald, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 501)
    - Macmillan, Duncan, 1986 Jan 23 (Box 11, Folder 502)
    - Macmillan, Harold, 1978 Feb 6 (Box 11, Folder 503)
    - McMordie, Colin, 1973-75 (Box 11, Folder 504)
    - MacNaughton, Angus I., 1970 Jun 6 (Box 11, Folder 505)
    - Magdalen College Development Trust, 1993-97 (Box 11, Folder 506)
    - Magnus, Philip, Sir, 1963-86 (Box 11, Folder 507)
    - Major, John, 1992 Nov 16 (Box 11, Folder 508)
    - Mallon, Michael, 1993-96 (Box 11, Folder 509)
    - Mander, Rosalie
      See: R. Glynn Grylls, Box 6, folder 315
    - Mandler, Peter, 1990-97 (Box 11, Folder 510)
    - Mansel, Philip, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 511)
    - Mansergh, Nicholas, 1978 May 27 (Box 11, Folder 512)
    - Marsh, Edward Howard, Sir, 1935-40, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 513)
    - Marshall, Bruce, 1973 Apr 23 (Box 11, Folder 514)
    - Marshall-Cornwall, James Handyside, Sir
    - Martin, Richard, 1995-96 (Box 11, Folder 515)
    - Martindale, C. C., 1932-33 (Box 11, Folder 516)
    - Mary, Princess Royal, Countess of Harewood, 1948, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 517)
      One letter written by the
      Princess Royal, others by
      ladies-in-waiting
    - Masson, Georgina (Babs Johnson), 1959 Dec 7, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 518)
    - Masters, Brian, 1980-95 (Box 11, Folder 519)
    - Matheson, Donald MacLeod
    - Maugham, Robin, 1978 May 8 (Box 11, Folder 520)
    - Maugham, W. Somerset, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 521)
    - Meade-Fetherstonhaugh, Margaret Ishbel Frances Glyn, Lady, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 522)
    - Meller, Hugh
    - Menuhin, Yehudi; Menuhin, Diana, 1964 Mar 27, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 523)
    - Meredith, Michael, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 524)
    - Messel, Oliver, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 525)
    - Messel, Thomas, 1990-94 (Box 11, Folder 526)
    - Methuen, Paul Ayshford Methuen, Baron, 1951, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 527)
    - Methuen-Campbell, James, 1988-96 (Box 11, Folder 528)
    - Miles, Paul; Miles, Rosie, 1990-95 (Box 11, Folder 529)
    - Miller, J. D. B., 1983-85 (Box 11, Folder 530)
    - Millington, Jon, 1982-97 (Box 11, Folder 531)
    - Milner, Violet Georgina Maxse, Viscountess, 1933, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 532)
    - Mitchell, Peter, 1984-89 (Box 11, Folder 533)
    - Mitford, Deborah
      See: Deborah, Duchess of Devonshire, Box 4, folder 204
    - Mitford, Diana
      See: Diana Mosley, Box 11, folder 548
    - Mitford, Jessica, 1970-86 (Box 11, Folder 534)
    - Mitford, Tom, 1932-33 (Box 11, Folder 535)
    - Moncreiff, Francis, Father, 1934-44 (Box 11, Folder 536)
    - Montgomery, Alberta Victoria ("Mrs Betty"), 1943 Oct 14, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 537)
    - Montgomery-Massingberd, Hugh, 1969-97 (Box 11, Folder 538)
    - Moore, Daphne, 1995, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 539)
    - Moore, Derry (Earl of Drogheda), 1987-97, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 540)
    - Moore, Doris Langley-Levy, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 541)
    - Moore, Jerrold Northrop, 1997 Aug 16 (Box 11, Folder 542)
    - Morris, Jan, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 543)
    - Morrison, Rosalind, 1993-94 (Box 11, Folder 544)
    - Mortimer, Penelope, 1984 May 28 (Box 11, Folder 545)
    - Mortimer, Raymond, 1958-78 (Box 11, Folder 546)
    - Mosley, Charlotte, 1990-93 (Box 11, Folder 547)
    - Mosley, Diana, Lady, 1926-30 (Box 11, Folder 548)
    - Mosley, Diana, Lady, 1963-90 (Box 11, Folder 549-551)
    - Mosley, Maud, 1934 Oct 29 (Box 11, Folder 552)
    - Moulton, Alex, 1970-97 (Box 11, Folder 553)
    - Mount, Ferdinand, 1995 Mar 22 (Box 12, Folder 554)
    - Murdoch, Elisabeth, Dame, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 555)
    - Murphy, Philip, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 556)
    - Murphy, Sophia, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 557)
    - Murray, John ("Jock"); Murray, Diana, 1933-93 (Box 12, Folder 558)
      See also: John Murray Ltd., Box 8, folder 409
    - Murry, John Middleton, 1939 Oct 27 (Box 12, Folder 559)
    - "N" general, 1950-97 (Box 12, Folder 560)
    - Napier, Charles, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 561)
    - Napier, Priscilla Hayter, 1995-96, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 562)
    - National Art-Collections Fund, 1985-91 (Box 12, Folder 563)
    - National Gallery of Art (Washington, D. C.), 1991-94 (Box 12, Folder 564)
    - National Heritage Memorial Fund (Box 12, Folder 565)
      Outgoing letter from JL-M to
      Lord Rothschild
    - National Trust, 1941-97 (Box 12, Folder 566-567)
    - Newman, John, 1986 Sep 8 (Box 12, Folder 568)
    - Nicholson, Shirley, 1992 Aug 24 (Box 12, Folder 569)
    - Nicolson, Adam, 1982-89 (Box 12, Folder 570)
    - Nicolson, Benedict, 1975-77 (Box 12, Folder 571)
    - Nicolson, David, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 572)
    - Nicolson, Harold George, Sir, 1933-66 (Box 12, Folder 573)
      See also: Series II, Writings, Correspondence of Harold Nicolson, Box 25, folders 942-953
    - Nicolson, Nigel, 1956-97 (Box 12, Folder 574)
    - Niggeman, Elvira, 1976-81 (Box 12, Folder 575)
      See also: Series II, Writings, Correspondence of Harold Nicolson, Box 23, folder 947
    - Noailles, Charles de, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 576)
    - Noel, Gerard, 1991, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 577)
    - Norwich, John Julius; Norwich, Mollie, 1982-97 (Box 12, Folder 578)
    - "O" general, 1940-97 (Box 12, Folder 579)
    - The Oldie, 1995-97 (Box 12, Folder 580)
    - Ollard, Richard Lawrence, 1983-84 (Box 12, Folder 581)
    - Orde, Peter; Orde, Lavinia, 1986-95 (Box 12, Folder 582)
    - Order of St. John, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 583)
    - Orwin, Charles, 1981-95 (Box 12, Folder 584)
    - Oxford University Press, 1932-96 (Box 12, Folder 585)
    - Oxford University Press / Dictionary of National Biography, 1976-97 (Box 12, Folder 586)
    - "P" general, 19[47]-97 (Box 12, Folder 587)
    - Palmer, Eileen, 1979-93 (Box 12, Folder 588)
    - Parkinson, Norman, 1978 May 12 (Box 12, Folder 589)
    - Parsons, Anthony, 1977 Apr 6 (Box 12, Folder 590)
    - Parsons, Desmond, 1933-37 (Box 12, Folder 591)
    - Parsons, Ian, 1976, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 592)
    - Paul VI, Pope, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 593)
    - Pavitt, Burnett, 1973-94 (Box 13, Folder 594)
    - Pavord, Anna, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 595)
    - Paxman, Jeremy, 1995 Aug 18 (Box 13, Folder 596)
    - [Pembroke?], Henry, [Earl of], 1995 Apr 15 (Box 13, Folder 597)
    - Pembroke, Sidney Charles, Earl of, 1962 Jul 18 (Box 13, Folder 598)
    - Pfeiffer, Andrew, 1976-95 (Box 13, Folder 599)
    - Phillips, John, 1976-83 (Box 13, Folder 600)
    - Piggott, Stuart, 1940 Feb 28 (Box 13, Folder 601)
    - Platzer, David, 1986-94 (Box 13, Folder 602)
    - Plomer, William, 1961-72 (Box 13, Folder 603)
    - Plumptre, George, 1983-96 (Box 13, Folder 604)
    - Polignac, Winnaretta, Princesse de, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 605)
    - Pollock, John Charles, 1989 Jan 31 (Box 13, Folder 606)
    - Poole, Keith B., 1970 Aug 20 (Box 13, Folder 607)
    - Pope-Hennessy, James, 1937-53, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 608)
      See also: Series II, Writings, Correspondence of Harold Nicolson, Box 23, folder 949
    - Pope-Hennessy, John, Sir, 1956-94 (Box 13, Folder 609)
      With 1994 photograph of John P-H
    - Pope-Hennessy, Una, 1937 Jan 17, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 610)
    - Portland, William Arthur Henry Bentinck, Duke of
    - Powell, Anthony, 1981-92 (Box 13, Folder 611)
    - Powell, Violet Georgiana, Lady, 1977-96 (Box 13, Folder 612)
    - Preston, Stuart, 1939-93, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 613-615)
      Letter of 1990 Jun 27 encloses
      a photograph of Preston
      See also: Series II, Writings, Correspondence of Harold Nicolson, Box 23, folder 950
    - Pryce-Jones, Alan, 1933, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 616)
    - Pryce-Jones, David, 1974, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 617)
    - Pym, Roland, 1992-97 (Box 13, Folder 618)
    - "Q" general, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 619)
    - Quennell, Marilyn, 1993-97 (Box 13, Folder 620)
    - Quennell, Peter, 1933-92 (Box 13, Folder 621)
    - "R" general, 1933-97 (Box 13, Folder 622)
    - Radcliffe, Everard, 1967-74 (Box 13, Folder 623)
    - Rae, Kenneth, 1970-83 (Box 13, Folder 624)
    - Raphael, Frederic, 1982 Jan 6 (Box 13, Folder 625)
    - Rathbone, Jack, 1975-85 (Box 13, Folder 626)
    - Ravenscroft-Hume, Ann, 1993-94 (Box 13, Folder 627)
    - Redesdale, Sydney, Lady, 1945-58 (Box 13, Folder 628)
    - Redgrave, Michael, Sir, 1966 Nov 29 (Box 13, Folder 629)
    - Reader, John, 1987 Oct 15 (Box 13, Folder 630)
    - Reed, Henry Hope, 1983 Jan 6 (Box 13, Folder 631)
    - Rees-Mogg, William, 1977 Nov 1 (Box 13, Folder 632)
      See also: The Times, Box 16, folder 759
    - Reid, Michaela, 1988 Apr 16 (Box 13, Folder 633)
    - Reid, Victoria, 1988-92 (Box 13, Folder 634)
      Photograph of Reid in 1913
      on Christmas card, n.d.
    - Reuters ltd., 1936 (Box 13, Folder 635)
    - Rhodes, Anthony, 1973-97 (Box 13, Folder 636)
    - Rice, Diane, 1994-95 (Box 13, Folder 637)
    - Rice, Tamara Talbot, 1943 Mar 22 (Box 13, Folder 638)
    - Richards, I. A., 1933 (Box 13, Folder 639)
    - Richards, J. M., Sir, 1986, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 640)
    - Richardson, A. E., Sir, 1942, 1945 (Box 13, Folder 641)
    - Richmond, Theo, 1975-86 (Box 13, Folder 642)
    - Ridgway, Maurice H., 1953 Jan 26 (Box 13, Folder 643)
      With photograph of stone screen
      at Bunbury Church, Cheshire
    - Ridley, Nicholas, 1987 Feb 18 (Box 13, Folder 644)
    - Roberts, Andrew, 1989 Mar 1 (Box 14, Folder 645)
    - Roberts, Brian, 1981-84 (Box 14, Folder 646)
    - Roberts, Hugh, 1991-94 (Box 14, Folder 647)
    - Robinson, Alan, 1990-97 (Box 14, Folder 648)
    - Robinson, John, 1984-93 (Box 14, Folder 649)
    - Robinson, Liz, 1993-97 (Box 14, Folder 650)
    - Rogers, Neville, 1953-72 (Box 14, Folder 651)
    - Rolt, L. T. C., 1970-71 (Box 14, Folder 652)
    - Rose, Kenneth, 1969-94 (Box 14, Folder 653)
    - Rosensweig, Saul, 1985 Dec 1 (Box 14, Folder 654)
    - Rosse, Anne Parsons, Countess of, 1982-88, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 655)
    - Rosse, (Laurence) Michael Harvey Parsons, Earl of, 1937-75 (Box 14, Folder 656)
    - Rousseau, George S., 1982-84 (Box 14, Folder 657)
    - Rowse, A. L., 1970-94 (Box 14, Folder 658)
      With photograph of architectural
      detail on a church in Somerset
    - Rowley, Joshua; Rowley, Celia, 1989, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 659)
    - Royal Greenwich Observatory, 1985-86 (Box 14, Folder 660)
    - Royal Society of Literature, 1982-97 (Box 14, Folder 661)
    - Rumbold, Richard, 1957, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 662)
    - Rushton, John, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 663)
    - Russell, John, 1978-87 (Box 14, Folder 664)
    - Ryan-Bell, Jeremy; Ryan-Bell, Carolyne, 1987-96 (Box 14, Folder 665)
    - Rylands, George ("Dadie"), 1978-91 (Box 14, Folder 666)
    - "S" general, 1933-97 (Box 14, Folder 667)
    - St. Clair-Erskine, Hamish, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 668)
    - St. John-Stevas, Norman, 1974, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 669)
    - St. Leven, Gwen, 1976-81 (Box 14, Folder 670)
    - Sach, Margaret, 1984-97 (Box 14, Folder 671)
    - Sackville-West, Edward, 1938-52 (Box 14, Folder 672)
    - Sackville-West, Vita, 1932-62, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 673)
      See also: Series II, Writings, Correspondence of Harold Nicolson, Box 23, folder 951
    - Sands, Ethel (Box 14, Folder 674)
    - Sansom, Katharine, 1970 Jul 25 (Box 14, Folder 675)
    - Saumarez Smith, John, 1975-94 (Box 14, Folder 676)
      See also: G. Heywood Hill Ltd., Box 5, folder 275
    - SAVE Britain's Heritage, 1984-92 (Box 14, Folder 677)
    - Scarfe, Norman, 1988 May 29 (Box 14, Folder 678)
    - Schleswig-Holstein, Helena Victoria, Princess of, 1940 Apr 18 (Box 14, Folder 679)
      Written by a lady-in-waiting
    - Schrijver, Elka, 1982-88 (Box 14, Folder 680)
      With two photographs, one of a
      house in scaffolding and one of
      men working in a quarry
    - Scotland, Tony, 1987-97 (Box 14, Folder 681)
    - Scott, David, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 682)
      See also: Series II, Writings, Correspondence of Harold Nicolson, Box 23, folder 953
    - Scott, Kathleen
      See: Kathleen Young, Lady Kennet, Box 8, folder 421
    - Scott, Peter, Sir, 1947-87 (Box 15, Folder 683)
    - Scott, Valerie (Valerie Finnis), 1986-96 (Box 15, Folder 684)
    - Sebba, Anne M., 1985-86 (Box 15, Folder 685)
    - Secrest, Meryle, 1980-97 (Box 15, Folder 686)
    - Seebohm, Caroline, 1987-88 (Box 15, Folder 687)
    - Setterwall, Ake, 1948 Oct 13 (Box 15, Folder 688)
    - Shaffer, Elinor, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 689)
    - Shakespeare, Nicholas, 1993, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 690)
      See also: Daily Telegraph, Box 4, folder 189
    - Shaw, George Bernard, 1944 (Box 15, Folder 691)
    - Shawe-Taylor, Desmond, 1951-95 (Box 15, Folder 692)
    - Sheehy, Eugene P., 1991 Jan 29 (Box 15, Folder 693)
    - Sheppard, F. H. W., 1985 Oct 27 (Box 15, Folder 694)
    - Sherard, Robert Harborough, 1934 Jan 8 (Box 15, Folder 695)
    - Sheridan, Clare, 1937, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 696)
    - Sherwood, Shirley, 1988 Aug 24 (Box 15, Folder 697)
    - Shone, Richard, 1977-97 (Box 15, Folder 698)
    - Sidgwick & Jackson Ltd., 1981-88 (Box 15, Folder 699)
    - Simpson, Colin, 1985 Feb 12 (Box 15, Folder 700)
    - Sinclair, Clive; Sinclair, Noel, 1991-92 (Box 15, Folder 701)
    - Sitwell, Constance Talbot, 1947 Aug 18 (Box 15, Folder 702)
    - Sitwell, Francis, 1992-97 (Box 15, Folder 703)
    - Sitwell, Georgia Doble, 1976 Aug 5 (Box 15, Folder 704)
    - Sitwell, Sacheverell, 1948-81 (Box 15, Folder 705)
    - Skinner, Martin, 1988 Aug 8 (Box 15, Folder 706)
    - Smallwood, Norah
      See: Chatto and Windus, Box 3, folder 129
    - Smith, H. Clifford, 1941, 1944 (Box 15, Folder 707)
    - Smith, John, 1962-86 (Box 15, Folder 708)
    - Smith, Logan Pearsall, 1943-45 (Box 15, Folder 709)
    - Smith, Roger Morsley, 1986-96 (Box 15, Folder 710)
    - Snell, Reginald, 1986 Apr 17 (Box 15, Folder 711)
    - Snowdon, Antony Armstrong-Jones, Earl of, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 712)
    - Sotheby & Co., 1990-92 (Box 15, Folder 713)
    - Spaight, George, 1970-97 (Box 15, Folder 714)
      See also: George Rainbird ltd., Box 6, folder 283
    - Sparrow, John, 1941-85 (Box 15, Folder 715)
      See also: Series II, Writings, Correspondence of Harold Nicolson, Box 23, folder 940
    - The Spectator, 1985-97 (Box 15, Folder 716)
    - Spencer, Albert Edward John Spencer, Earl, 1943 Oct 11 (Box 15, Folder 717)
    - Spender, Natasha, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 718)
    - Spender, Stephen, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 719)
    - Spurling, Hilary, 1981-83, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 720)
    - Sprawson, Charles, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 721)
    - Stamp, Gavin, 1982-95 (Box 15, Folder 722)
    - Stewart, Madeau, 1983-91 (Box 15, Folder 723)
    - Stewart-Jones, Elizabeth ("Beanie"), 1996 Jan 30, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 724)
    - Stewart-Jones, Richard, 1938-42 (Box 15, Folder 725)
      With outgoing letters from
      JL-M to RS-J, 1938-41, one letter
      to RS-J from Anne Chamberlain, 1940,
      and one to Mrs. Stewart-Jones from
      Pamela J. Gordon, 1940.
    - Steyn, Mark, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 726)
    - Stockdale, F. M. ("Freddie"), 1992 (Box 15, Folder 727)
    - Stone, Humphrey; Stone, Solveig, 1988-97 (Box 15, Folder 728)
    - Stone, Janet, 1969-96, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 729)
    - Stone, Reynolds, 1950-80 (Box 15, Folder 730)
    - Strickland, Margot, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 731)
    - Strong, Roy C., 1974-89 (Box 15, Folder 732)
    - Stroud District Council, 1991-92 (Box 15, Folder 733)
    - Stroud, Dorothy, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 734)
    - Subercaseaux, Paz, 1995-97 (Box 15, Folder 735)
    - Sudley, Lord, 1987-89 (Box 15, Folder 736)
    - Summerson, John Newenham, 1946-48 (Box 15, Folder 737)
    - Sunday Express Magazine, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 738)
    - Sunday Telegraph, 1988-97 (Box 15, Folder 739)
    - Surtees, Virginia, 1988-96, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 740)
    - Sutro, John; Sutro, Gillian, 1980-85, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 741)
    - Sutton, Denys, 1976-89 (Box 16, Folder 742)
    - Sykes, Christopher, 1968-88 (Box 16, Folder 743)
    - "T" general, 1935-97 (Box 16, Folder 744)
    - Tait, Frank, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 745)
    - Templer, Gerald, Sir, 1972 Jan 17 (Box 16, Folder 746)
    - Tennant, Emma, 1989-94 (Box 16, Folder 747)
    - Tennant, P. E., 1991 Sep 25 (Box 16, Folder 748)
    - Textile Conservation Centre, 1995-97 (Box 16, Folder 749)
    - Thatcher, Margaret, 1991 Apr 24 (Box 16, Folder 750)
    - Thesiger, Ernest, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 751)
    - Thesiger, Wilfred, 1987-88 (Box 16, Folder 752)
    - Thomas, Graham Stuart, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 753)
    - Thomas Lovell Beddoes Society, 1994, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 754)
    - [Thorneycroft?], Carla, 1994-95 (Box 16, Folder 755)
    - Thorold, Henry, 1970-94 (Box 16, Folder 756)
    - Throckmorton, Clare McLaren, 1991-92 (Box 16, Folder 757)
    - Till, Barry, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 758)
    - The Times [London], 1972-97 (Box 16, Folder 759)
    - Tollemache, Humphrey, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 760)
    - Tolstoy, Nikolai, 1989-90 (Box 16, Folder 761)
    - Tomlinson, Charles, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 762)
    - Trefusis, Violet, 1970, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 763)
    - Trevelyan, G. M., 1942-45 (Box 16, Folder 764)
    - Trevor-Roper, Patrick, 1987-95 (Box 16, Folder 765)
    - Trinnick, Michael, 1991-93 (Box 16, Folder 766)
    - [Twichell?], Ann, 1992-97 (Box 16, Folder 767)
    - "U" general, 1997, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 768)
    - "V" general, 1941-96 (Box 16, Folder 769)
    - Vaizey, John, 1977-83 (Box 16, Folder 770)
    - Varma, Devendra P., 1985-90 (Box 16, Folder 771)
    - Verey, David, 1970, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 772)
    - Verey, Rosemary, 1994-97, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 773)
    - Verney, Theodosia Cropper, 1993-95, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 774)
    - Vicary, David, 1984-92 (Box 16, Folder 775)
    - [Vickers?], Hugo, 1990-96 (Box 16, Folder 776)
    - Villeneuve, Guillaume, 1989-97 (Box 16, Folder 777)
    - Vuoles, Edward, 1986-89 (Box 16, Folder 778)
    - "W" general, 1926-97 (Box 16, Folder 779)
    - Wagner, Anthony Richard, Sir; Wagner, Gillian, 1952-95 (Box 16, Folder 780)
    - Walker, Ethel, 1945 Mar 7, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 781)
    - Wall, Derek, 1987 Jul 20, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 782)
    - Wall, Christopher; Wall, Francesca, 1966-94 (Box 16, Folder 783)
    - Wallace, Carrew, 1989-91 (Box 16, Folder 784)
    - Wallis, Peter J. L., 1988-93 (Box 16, Folder 785)
    - Wansbrough, Elizabeth, 1974-87 (Box 16, Folder 786)
    - War Office, 1940-43 (Box 16, Folder 787)
    - Warren, Thomas Herbert, Sir, 1928-30 (Box 16, Folder 788)
    - Warrick, Christopher, 1984 Oct (Box 16, Folder 789)
    - Waterson, Merlin
    - Watkin, David, 1975, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 790)
    - Watson, Francis, 1992 Feb 28 (Box 16, Folder 791)
    - Waugh, Evelyn, 1945 Jun 24 (Box 16, Folder 792)
      With letter from Waugh
      to Nancy Mitford [1963]
    - Weatherhead, A. Kingsley, 1981 Jan 21 (Box 16, Folder 793)
    - Weideger, Paula, 1992 Mar 2 (Box 16, Folder 794)
    - Weidenfeld and Nicolson, 1987-97 (Box 16, Folder 795)
    - Weinreb, Ben, 1976 May 6 (Box 16, Folder 796)
    - Welch, Denton, 1945 Sep 7 (Box 16, Folder 797)
    - Wellington, Gerald Wellesley, Duke of, 1944-78 (Box 16, Folder 798)
    - Wengrow, Arnold, 1984 May 8 (Box 16, Folder 799)
    - Wesierska, Ruth Walder, 1987-94 (Box 16, Folder 800)
      With photograph of Goslice Plock,
      home of Major General Wesierski
    - Westminster Cathedral, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 801)
    - Whinney, Margaret Dickens, 1952 May 8 (Box 17, Folder 802)
    - Wilkes, Lyall, 1983-86 (Box 17, Folder 803)
    - Williams-Ellis, Clough, 1974-75 (Box 17, Folder 804)
    - [Willis?], Peggy, 1991-95 (Box 17, Folder 805)
    - Wilson, Andrew, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 806)
    - Wilson, Ian, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 807)
    - Wilson, Margaret, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 808)
    - Wilton-Ely, John, 1975-94 (Box 17, Folder 809)
    - Windsor Castle Library, 1973-97 (Box 17, Folder 810)
      Letters from librarians
      Robin Mackworth-Young and
      Oliver Everett
      See also: Series II, The Last Stuarts, Box 24, folder 962
    - Winn, Elizabeth, 1977-97 (Box 17, Folder 811)
    - Wisternoff, David, 1991-92 (Box 17, Folder 812)
    - Witts, Francis, 1984-96 (Box 17, Folder 813)
    - Woolf, Virginia; Woolf, Leonard
      See: Series II, Writings, Correspondence of Harold Nicolson, Box 23, folder 952
    - Woolley, Leonard, Sir
      See: War Office, Box 16, folder 787
    - Worsley, Marcus, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 814)
    - Wright, Patrick, 1988-90 (Box 17, Folder 815)
    - Wright, Ronald Selby, 1991 May 15 (Box 17, Folder 816)
    - Wrigley, Beatrice; Wrigley, Edith, 1988-97 (Box 17, Folder 817)
    - Wyatt, Woodrow, 1984 Mar 12 (Box 17, Folder 818)
    - "Y-Z" general, 1976-95, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 819)
    - Yoss, Michael, 1995-97 (Box 17, Folder 820)
    - Young, G. M., n.d. (Box 17, Folder 821)
    - Young, Louisa, 1993-95 (Box 17, Folder 822)
    - Young, Rory, 1988-97 (Box 17, Folder 823)
  - FAMILY CORRESPONDENCE
    - Bailey, Gwladys, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 824)
    - Cunninghame, Doreen, 1939, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 825)
    - De L'Isle, Margaret, 1976-95 (Box 17, Folder 826)
    - Lees-Milne, Alvilde, 1981-89 (Box 17, Folder 827)
    - Lees-Milne, Dorothy, 1935-53 (Box 17, Folder 828)
    - Lees-Milne, Elaine, 1985-90 (Box 17, Folder 829)
    - Lees-Milne, George Crompton, 1935-49 (Box 17, Folder 830)
    - Lees-Milne, Guy, 1983-93 (Box 17, Folder 831)
    - Lees-Milne, Helen, 19[20s]-62 (Box 17, Folder 832-834)
      With letter to HL-M from
      V. C. Buckley, 1939 Oct 5
    - Lees-Milne, Mary, 1932-35 (Box 17, Folder 835)
    - Lees-Milne, Richard Crompton, 1940-63 (Box 17, Folder 836)
    - Lees-Milne, Simon; Lees-Milne, Tricia, 1988-96 (Box 17, Folder 837)
    - Luke, Chloë; Luke, Kane, 1988-95 (Box 17, Folder 838)
    - Luke, Clarissa, 1993-97 (Box 17, Folder 839)
    - Luke, Igor, 1991-95 (Box 17, Folder 840)
    - Luke, Michael, 1991-95 (Box 17, Folder 841)
    - Luke, Oenone, 1989-97 (Box 17, Folder 842)
      With photograph of Ismene
      Luke's christening, 1997
    - Luke, Peter, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 843)
    - Milnes-Gaskell, Constance, Lady, 1939-48, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 844)
    - Robinson, Alice, 1990, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 845)
    - Robinson, Henry, 1984-96 (Box 17, Folder 846)
    - Robinson, Nick, 1979-97, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 847)
    - Robinson, Prudence, 1939, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 848)
    - Robinson, Richard, 1988-97 (Box 17, Folder 849)
    - Stevens, Audrey, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 850)
    - Thompson, Maggie, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 851)
    - "Joanna", 1988-89 (Box 17, Folder 852)